A Finding Aid to the C. J. (Clarence Joseph) Bulliet Papers, circa 1888-1959, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bullclar
Archives of American Art
C. J. (Clarence Joseph) Bulliet papers
circa 1888-1959
AAA.bullclar
Archives of American Art
34.6 Linear feet
The C. J. (Clarence Joseph) Bulliet papers measure 34.6 linear feet and are dated circa 1888-1959. Biographical materials, correspondence, writings, subject and artist files, printed material, photographs, and artwork document the career of the influential Chicago art critic and writer. The records contain extensive information about art and artists in Chicago and the Midwest from the early to mid-twentieth century.
Bulliet, C.J., 1883-1952
Biographical Note
Known for his support of modernism, C. J. Bulliet spent the majority of his long newspaper career in Chicago. Born Clarence Joseph Bulleit in Corydon, Indiana, he studied English, astronomy, and mathematics at Indiana University. After graduating in 1905, he became a member of the Indiana University Total Eclipse Expedition to Spain in its search for a planet within Mercury's orbit. During World War I the spelling to Bulliet was changed to avoid any connection with Germany.
Upon returning to the United States, Bulliet began his newspaper career as a reporter for the Louisville Herald, soon moved to the Indianapolis Star as a police reporter, and eventually was named its drama critic. Between 1912 and 1921, he traveled extensively throughout the country as a press agent for Shakespearean actor Robert B. Mantell. During this period, he published his first book, a biography titled Robert Mantell's Romance. World War I interrupted Mantell's tour for two years, during which time Bulliet was press representative for D. W. Griffith's Birth of a Nation. He returned to the Louisville Herald for two years before moving to Chicago.
In 1923, the Chicago Evening Post established "The Art World Magazine," a weekly tabloid section reporting local, national, and international art news. C.J. Bulliet became the magazine's first (and only) editor. In addition, he served as the paper's drama critic. When the Chicago Evening Post was sold in 1932, becoming the Chicago Daily News, Bulliet was appointed its art critic. Although Bulliet was an experienced reporter, writer, and editor with a broad general knowledge of theater and drama, he had virtually no background in art or art history. An avid reader, he was determined to learn as much as he could, and managed to make himself an expert in a relatively short time. From 1924 until his death in 1952, C. J. Bulliet was the most important art critic in Chicago. His strong support of modernism and the gossipy, entertaining style of his columns made him a popular and controversial figure with great local influence on public opinion, exhibitions, and patronage. In addition to his work on the Chicago newspapers, C. J. Bulliet contributed articles to Art Digest, the New York Times, and other national publications.
Once established as an art editor and critic, C. J. Bulliet began writing extensively on art, and published many books on the subject for general readers. The first, Apples and Madonnas: Emotional Expression in Modern Art (1927), was extremely well-received and remained in print through many editions. Other titles include: Tour of the Exhibition of the Works of Alexander Archipenko (1927), The Courtezan Olympia: An Intimate Survey of Artists and their Mistress-Models (1930), Art Masterpieces: In a Century of Progress Fine Art Exhibition at the Art Institute of Chicago (1933), Paintings, An Introduction to Art (1934); The Significant Moderns and Their Pictures (1936), Masterpieces of Italian Art (1939), French Art from David to Matisse: As Set Forth in 20 Masterpieces of the French Exhibit at the Art Institute of Chicago (1941), Art Treasures from Vienna (1949), and The Story of Lent in Art (1951). He published books on other subjects, as well. In addition to his 1918 biography of Robert B. Mantell, they are: Venus Castina: Famous Female Impersonators, Celestial and Human (1933) and How Grand Opera Came to Chicago (1940-1941).
Scope and Content Note
The C. J. Bulliet papers measure 34.6 linear feet and are dated circa 1888-1959. Biographical materials, correspondence, writings, subject and artist files, printed material, photographs, and artwork document the career of the influential Chicago art critic and writer. The records contain extensive information about art and artists in Chicago and the Midwest from the early to mid-twentieth century.
Biographical materials, circa 1888-1952, about C. J. Bulliet and his artist wife, Katherine Adams Bulliet, include Adams family genealogy, biographical notes, inventory and notes about Bulliet's art collection, miscellaneous items, and photographs. Photographs include portraits of C. J. Bulliet as a young child, and photographs around the time of his graduation from Indiana University. Other photographs are group shots of Bulliet with Mrs. Bulliet, Millard Sheets, Mr. and Mrs. Peyton Boswell, Jr., James Chapin, the Chicago Daily News staff, and other Chicago art critics.
Correspondence, 1901-1942, documents Bulliet's professional and personal life. Professional correspondence provides a good overview of the art scene, activities, and attitudes in Chicago during the 1930s and 1940s. Many letters from newspaper readers contain both positive and negative reactions to his columns. Personal correspondence consists mainly of letters Bulliet wrote to his wife while on the road with Robert Mantell and his Shakespeare company. Other personal correspondence is with friends and relatives, and includes some letters addressed to Katherine Adams Bulliet.
Writings, 1929-1951, consist of notes, drafts, and final manuscripts of published and unpublished articles and essays, books, fiction and poems, lectures, and reviews by C. J. Bulliet. A small number of manuscripts are by other authors.
Artist files, 1919-1952, document a wide variety of artists from the Renaissance through the mid-twentieth century. Artists represented are American, European, and Asian; of particular interest are files relating to Chicago area artists, both well known and obscure. They consist largely of photographs of works of art and a small number of photographs of artists. A small percentage includes correspondence, notes and drafts of texts by Bulliet, printed material, and a few original prints.
Subject files, 1909-1952, concern topics that interested Bulliet. They consist mainly of photographs and printed material, with a small amount of correspondence.
Printed material, 1909-1959, by Bulliet consists of newspaper articles and columns, books, and reviews of art, books, and music. Items produced by others include books, clippings, museum and art school publications, periodicals, and press releases. Exhibition related items, consisting of announcements, invitations, catalogs, checklists, and prospectuses, are categorized by venues - Chicago and elsewhere.
Art work, 1916-1948, mainly by Chicago area artists, consists of prints, drawings, and a sketchbook, most likely given to Bulliet by the artists themselves.
Arrangement
Series 2: Correspondence, Series 4: Artist Files, Series 5: Subject Files, and Series 7: Artwork are arranged alphabetically. Other series, organized by record type, are arranged chronologically within each category, as noted in the series descriptions/container listing below.
The collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, circa 1888-1952 (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1901-1952 (Boxes 1-2; 2 linear ft.)
Series 3: Writings, 1929-1951 (Boxes 3-4; 2 linear ft.)
Series 4: Artist Files, 1919-1952 (Boxes 5-24; 20 linear ft.)
Series 5: Subject Files, 1909-1952 (Boxes 25-27, 37; 2.3 linear ft.)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1909-1959 (Boxes 27-34, 36-37; 7.7 linear ft.)
Series 7: Artwork, 1916-1948 (Boxes 35, 38, OV 39; 0.6 linear ft.)
Provenance
The papers were donated to the Archives in 1984 by C. J. Bulliet's son, Lender J. Bulliet. Additional records were given by Rockford College, Rockford, Illinois, in 1987.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Bulliet, Katherine Adams; Chapin, James, 1887-1975; Mantell, Robert B., (Robert Bruce), 1854-1928; Sheets, Millard, 1907-1989; Art criticism -- Illinois -- Chicago; Art critics -- Illinois -- Chicago; Art, Modern -- 20th century --Illinois --Chicago; Artists -- Illinois -- Chicago; Drawings; Modernism (Art); Photographs; Prints; Sketchbooks; United States -- Social life and customs
- Biographical Materials, circa 1888-1952; Series 1; 6 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Photographs of Clarence J. Bulliet include studio portraits. Two, circa 1905, are likely college graduation pictures. Those of Bulliet with others include a portrait of him at about age 5 with his sister. Identified individuals in other group shots are: Mrs. Bulliet, Millard Sheets, Mr. and Mrs. Peyton Boswell, Jr.; Peyton Boswell, Jr. and James Chapin; Joseph Luyber and James Chapin; Eleanor Jewett, Frank Holland, and Copeland Burg; Chicago Daily News staff; Walter J. Sherwood; Copeland Burg and Lester Bridaham; and heavily tattooed wrestlers.
  The file relating to the Bulliet Art Collection includes sales receipts, notes, and estate inventory records. Miscellaneous items include business cards and checkbooks.
  The file concerning Adams family genealogy includes both research correspondence and letters from family members containing relevant information. Additional Adams family letters are filed with Series 2: Correspondence.
  - Adams Family Genealogy (Katherine Adams Bulliet), 1914-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Notes, circa 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bulliet Art Collection, 1925-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Items, 1910s-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Clarence J. Bulliet, circa 1905-circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of C. J. Bulliet with Others, circa 1888-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1901-1952; Series 2; 2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Professional and personal correspondence consists mainly of incoming letters, with some carbon copies of Bulliet's outgoing letters. This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Professional correspondence with galleries, museums, artists, arts and artists' organizations, and newspaper readers provides a good overview of the art scene, activities, and attitudes in Chicago during the 1930s and 1940s. Many letters are from readers commenting on Bulliet's newspaper columns, typically with an enclosed clipping of the column in question. Included among the correspondence are Christmas and other greeting cards, many with original artwork.
  Personal correspondence is with friends, relatives, and his wife, Katherine Adams Bulliet. The letters from Bulliet to his wife were written while he was traveling for extended periods in 1912-1915, acting as publicity agent for the Shakespearean actor and producer Robert B. Mantell.
  A small number of family letters including genealogical information relating to the family of Katherine Adams Bulliet are filed with Biographical Information. In addition, small amounts of correspondence are scattered among the Artist Files and Subject Files.
  - Abbott, Jere - Acosta y Calderon, Edgardo, 1928-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Abbott, Jere
    Harry N. Abrams Incorporated
    Acosta Y Calderon, Edgardo
  - Adams Family (various relatives of Katherine Adams Bulliet), 1912-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Albright, Ivan Le Loraine - Alten, Matias J., 1924-1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Albright, Ivan Le Loraine
    Aldis, Arthur T.
    Alexanderson, Genevieve
    Alinari Fratellil
    Allmond, Peg
    Allied Arts Corporation
    Alling, Charles
    Alten, Matias J.
  - American Art Annual - American Spectator, 1923-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    American Art Annual
    American Art Research Council
    American Artists' Congress, Inc.
    American Concert Management
    American Federation of Arts
    American Jewish Arts Club
    American Liberty League
    American School of Design
    American Spectator
  - Anapol, Bert - Arquin, Florence, 1923-1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Anapol, Bert
    Anderson, Laura
    Anderson, Paul F.
    Anderson, Mrs. Russell
    Angel, Rifka
    Anti-War Ball
    Archbold, Geoffrey
    Archipenko, Alexander
    Argus
    Armin, Emil
    Armstrong, Ned
    Arossainy, Howard
    Arquin, Florence
  - Art Digest - Art Directors Club of Chicago, 1932-1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Art Digest
    Art Directors Club of Chicago
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1933-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Artists and Models Ball - Artists Union of Chicago, 1935-1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Artists and Models Ball
    Artists' Dream Ball
    Artists Equity Association
    Artists Equity of America
    Artists Guild of Chicago
    Artists League of the Midwest
    Artists Union of Chicago
  - Arts Club of Chicago - Baer, Martin, 1928-1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Arts Club of Chicago
    Arts Weekly
    Ashcraft, Charlotte P.
    Associated American Artists Galleries
    Association for Color Research
    Association of Chicago Painters and Sculptors
    Atlantic City Press
    Atwater, Adeline L.
    Aucello, Salvatore
    Badger, Frances P.
    Baer, Martin
  - Bahnc, Salcia, 1924-1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bailey, F.K. - Bertini, John, 1928-1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Bailey, F.K.
    Balaban, John
    Ballet Guild
    Balzac Galleries
    Barnes, Albert C.
    Barrett, Storrs B.
    Barron, Edith
    Barrows, Tom
    Bartlett, Clay
    Barton, Macena
    Barzel, Istar
    Bastien, Grace
    Batten, R. A.
    Baumann, Rena
    Beach, Burton
    Beach, Cy and Flossie
    Beard, Irma
    Beck, Joseph S.
    Becker, John
    Bennett, Edward
    Benedict-Brout, Robert
    Beniger, Louis
    Benjamin Galleries
    Berkman-Hunter, Bernece
    Berkson, Ethel M.
    Berkson, Maurice
    Berman, Mrs. J.
    Bernstein, Theresa
    Bertini, John
  - Biesel, Lucas - Briscoe, Charles F. and Harriet, 1927-1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Biesel, Lucas
    Bignou Gallery
    Bismarck Hotel
    Blackshear, Kathleen
    Blake, Charles G.
    Blencoe, Arthur J.
    Bleyer, Leo F.
    Bluemner, Oscar
    Blue Ribbon Books
    Blumenschein, Ernest L.
    Board of Jewish Education
    Bohrod, Aaron
    Bolton, B.B.
    Bontoux, A.
    Bosch, Imogene L.
    Boucicault, Ruth Holt
    Bouslog, Ena Mae
    Braun, Lilian Jackson
    Braunum, H.R. "Lumpy"
    Breen, Pat
    Brein, Mr. and Mrs. John David
    Brentano's
    Brewster, Kate R.
    Brewster, Walter S.
    Brewster, William
    Brickell, Herschel
    Bridaham, Lester and Dorothy Malanie Odenheimer
    Bridgman Publishers
    Briscoe, Charles F. and Harriet
  - Britton, Nan, 1928-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brod, Fritzi - Buffalo Fine Arts Academy/Albright Art Gallery, 1931-1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Brod, Fritzi
    Bronesky, S.S.
    Brout, Genevieve and Bob
    Brown, C.H.
    Brown, Ethel C.
    Newman Brown Gallery
    Brownell-Lambertson Galleries, Inc.
    Browning, George
    Brozik, Jaroslav
    Buchholz Gallery
    Buchta, Anthony
    Buck, Claude
    Buffalo Fine Arts Academy/Albright Art Gallery
  - Bulliet Family, 1915-1947 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bulliet, Jack (son) and Mildred (daughter in law?), 1912-1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bulliet, Katherine Adams (wife), 1912-1940 (Box 1, Folder 23-25)
  - Burg, Copeland C. - Cheney, Martha, 1914-1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Burg, Copeland C.
    Burgoyne, Martha
    Burrows, Peggy Palmer
    Bush, Mrs. William Henry
    Buttith, Tony
    Button, W. Russell
    Bye, Arthur Edwin
    Cadman, Charles Wakefield
    Caldwell, Orval
    Cameron, Edgar S.
    Campbell, Marjorie Dunn
    Canfield, Bitha J.
    Capital Journal
    Carlson, W.A.
    Carnegie Institute
    Carroll, Albert
    Cassady, Edithe Jane
    Carwin, Kathryn
    Cassell, Naomi Sherwood
    Cassman, Arthur
    Chapin, Mary
    Chase, Richard A.
    Chatt, Thomas J.
    Cheney, Martha
  - Chicago Academy of Fine Arts - Chicago's New Century Committee, 1929-1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Chicago Academy of Fine Arts
    Chicago Annual Pot-Pourri
    Chicago Artists Equity
    Chicago Board of Education
    Chicago Committee for Bureau of Fine Arts
    Chicago Daily News
    Chicago Evening Post
    Chicago Flower Show
    Chicago Galleries Association
    Chicago Journal of Commerce
    Chicago Newspaper Guild
    Chicago No-Jury Society of Artists
    Chicago Opera Company
    Chicago Park District
    Chicago Public Library
    Chicago Railroad Fair
    Chicago Society of Artists, Inc.
    Chicago Sun
    Chicago Symphony Orchestra
    Chicago Woman's Aid
    Chicago's Charter Jubilee
    Chicago's New Century Committee
  - Choinska, Marion S. - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1935-1950 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Choinska, Marion S.
    Christy, C.
    Citizens Committee for Government Arts Projects
    Claire, June
    Claremont Colleges
    Clark, Harry
    Cleveland Museum of Art
  - Cody, John A. - Council of Catholic Women, 1913-1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Cody, John A., Jr.
    Cohen, Leonard
    Cohen, Rosa
    Cole, Ellis Prentice
    Colin, Edward C.
    College Art Association
    Collins, Charles
    Community and War Fund of Metropolitan Chicago, Inc.
    Conner, S. I.
    Cooke, Le Baron
    Coolman, Hundley E.
    Co-operative Extension Work
    Cooperative Symphony Orchestra
    The Cordon
    Corydon Public Library
    Cosmopolis Press
    Coughlin, Robert
    Council of Catholic Women
  - Covici, Friede Inc., 1927-1940 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
  - Crain, I. - Detwiller, Frederick K., 1929-1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Crain, I.
    Cranmer, Catherine
    Creative Art
    Crown Publishers
    Cunningham, Inez
    Cunningham, P. T.
    Dahlgreen, Charles W.
    Dalstrom, Gustaf and Frances Foy
    Dalton, Virginia and Marie O'Hara
    Datur, Jay
    Datz, A. Mark
    Davenport Democrat
    Davidson, Donald
    Davis, Philip R.
    Dawson, Mitchell
    Deachman, Nelly
    Dean, Helga
    De Batty, B.
    Delchan, Ernest
    Delmar, Kenny
    De Mont, Nathalia
    De Paris, Henriette
    Des Plaines Woman's Club
    Despres, Edward
    Detwiller, Frederick K.
  - Dickey, Alice Mannery - Dyer, Harold I., 1924-1950 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Dickey, Alice Mannery
    Dickson, John W.
    Dietrich, Henry J.
    Diggs, Arthur
    Dillard, Irving
    Disney, Walt
    Ditto, Linda
    Dja, Devi
    Donaghey, Frederick
    D'Orsay, Nordica
    Doster, Irma
    Doubleday, Page, and Co./Doubleday, Doran and Company, Inc.
    Douglass, Helen E.
    Downtown Gallery
    Draves, Albert W.G., Jr.
    Drevn, Philip
    Dreyfuss, Ernest
    Dudensing, Valentine
    Dulac, Peg Walker
    Duncan, John C.
    Dunham, Katherine
    Dupee, Helen
    Durand-Ruel, Inc.
    Duval, G.
    Dyer, Harold S.
  - Edey, Maitland A. - Evanston Art Center, 1919-1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Edey, Maitland, A.
    Edwards, Louise B.
    Ehlscherd, Gertrude A.
    Ellsworth, Edith
    Eltinge, Julian
    Englander, Roger L.
    Engers, Angna
    Epperly, Rose and Richard
    Epstein, Max
    Equity of Chicago Artists
    Erbaugh, Ralph
    Erickson, Elmer
    Esquire
    Evanston Art Center
  - Fagen, Mildred R. - Fish, Helen Frances, 1933-1951 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Fagen, Mildred R.
    Faggi, Alfeo
    Failing, Frances
    The Fair
    Fairbanks, Avard
    Falk, Frank F.
    Feder, A.
    Federal Works Agency
    Ferguson, Agnes
    Fetridge, W. H.
    Fied, Benny
    Field, Jessie
    Fiesel, Charles
    Fifth Ward Art Center Committee
    Findlay Galleries Inc.
    Fine, L. M.
    Finlayson, Alec W.
    First American Congress for Aesthetics
    First Overseas Exposition of American Art
    Fischer, Mary
    Fish, Helen Frances
  - Ford, Elizabeth M. - Fry, Rowena, 1928-1951 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Ford, Elizabeth M.
    Ford's Opera House
    Fortune
    Fort Custer Station Hospital
    Four Arts
    Fowler, Eva
    Fox, Albert E.
    Fox, Robert
    Foy, Frances (Mrs. Gustaf Dalstrom)
    Frain, N. M.
    France, Consul General for
    Franta, Dorothy
    Frederick, George
    The Freeman
    Freeman, Charles K.
    Freeman, Shaindel K.
    Rose Fried Gallery
    Freidel, Albert H.
    Friends of Music of Chicago
    Frisch, Jeanette
    Fry, Rowena
  - Gabriel, Greta - Glick, Norman, 1932-1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Gabriel, Greta
    Gallo, Fortune
    Gannon, Tom
    Gardner, Mildlred
    Garrison, Eve
    Gaug, Margaret Ann
    Gaunt, W.
    Geneva Lake Art Association
    Gladchenko, Orloff
    Glaman, Eugenie F.
    Glasser, Anne K.
    Glatter, Magda
    Glicenstein, Enrico
    Glick, Norman
  - Goldblatt, Hilda - Harding, Elizabeth Anne, 1924-1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Goldblatt, Hilda
    Goldstone, Adele Hoskins
    Julius Goodman and Son, Inc.
    Goodnow, Anna N.
    Goodspeed, Edmund
    Goossens, Mrs. John
    Gordon, Donald A.
    Goriasky, L. K.
    Gough, Eva
    Gould, Wesley L.
    Graham, Sheila
    Grand Central Art Galleries
    Granville, Rachel
    Greene, Margaret
    Greenfield, Frances
    Gregory, Alice Hall
    Griffin, Nina K.
    Griggs, Jane Quinly
    Griston, Morris J.
    Gross, Earl
    Groves, D. F.
    Gulden, Peter
    Gutman, Amy
    Hagan, Oskar
    Haight, George I.
    Hall, C. L.
    Halt, George R.
    Hamilton, Russel D.
    Handley, Catherine
    Hansen, Dobriela
    Harbison, Katherine
    Harding, Elizabeth Anne
  - Harper and Brothers Publishers - Hirshburg, Roy, 1923-1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Harper and Brothers Publishers
    Marie Harriman Gallery
    Harrison, Preston
    Hartford, George
    Hartman, Sadakichi
    Harey, Victoria Unrich
    Harwood, Helen
    Haswell, Ernest Bruce
    Hawthorne, Mrs. Charles W.
    Hazelwood, Phoebe W.
    Headland, Helen
    Heath, Mrs. Ray
    Heckman, Winifred
    Herrin Daily Journal
    Hicks, Joseph W.
    Hill, Edith Healy
    Hill, Harriet Baillet
    Hilton, Emeline L.
    Hinckley, Lawrence B.
    Hinr, Denzil
    Hirshburg, Roy
  - Hoagland, Claire Page - Hunt, Lewis W., 1924-1951 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Hoagland, Claire Page
    Hobbs, Morris Henry
    Hochsinger, Gloria
    Hoerle, Helen
    Hoerman, Carl
    Hohenberg, Marguerite
    Holland Festival
    Hollister, Burton J.
    Hong, Anna
    Hoosier Salon Patrons Association
    Horn, Milton and Estelle
    Horner, Henry (Governor of Illinois)
    Horowitz, Vladimir
    Houston, Betty Ann
    Hoyt, Vivian Church
    Hubbard, Mrs. H. R.
    R.W. Huebsch, Inc., Publisher
    Hull House
    Hungerland, Helmut
    Hunt, Lewis W.
  - Hunter, George L. C. and Irene, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Hutchins, Maude Phelps - Indiana Artists Club, 1911-1942 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Hutchins, Maude Phelps
    Hutchinson, Gertrude E.
    Hutchinson, R. M.
    Hutty, Alfred
    Independent Moving Pictures Company of America
    Indiana Artists Club
  - Indiana University - Indiana University Foundation, 1905-1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Indiana University
    Indiana University Alumni Quarterly
    Indiana University Foundation
    Indiana University Library
  - Indianapolis Star - Jonsson, Norman, 1932-1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Indianapolis Star
    Institute for Psychoanalysis
    Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston
    Institute of Design (see also School of Design)
    Instituto Allende
    Iralson, Adel
    Isaacson, Charles D.
    Jackson, Roy
    Jaseph, Mr. and Mrs. Malcolm B.
    Jeck, Clement
    Jeritza, Maria
    Jewett, Eleanor
    John Reed Club
    Johnson, Anne
    Jones, Aaron J., Jr.
    Jones, Dan Burne
    Jones, Elsie
    Jones, Llewelyn
    Jones, Spike
    Jonsson, Norman
  - Kalish, Shaindel - Kelly, Edward J., 1927-1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Kalish, Shaindel
    K.A.M. Temple
    Kamara, Mamadou
    Kaplan, Bernard
    Kappa Kappa Kappa, Inc.
    Karfiol, Bernard
    Katz, A. Raymond
    Katz, Leo